From the day we arrive
우리 이 땅 위에
On the planet
태어나서
And, blinking, step into the sun
흙으로 돌아갈 때까지
There's more to see
해야 할 일
Than can ever be seen
하고 싶은 일이
More to do
세상에
Than can ever be done
너무 많이 있어
There's far too much
돌아보면
To take in here
짧은 시간
More to find
아쉬움
Than can ever be found
가득하지만
But the sun rolling high
고개 들어보면
Through the sapphire sky
저기 하늘 끝에
Keeps great and small
우리 낙원
On the endless round
널리 펼쳐져
It's the circle of life
모두 살아가는
And it moves us all
끝이 없는 길
Through despair and hope
고난이 와도
Through faith and love
함께하면
Till we find our place
언젠간 우리
On the path unwinding
낙원을 찾겠지
In the circle
희망 안고
The circle of life
우리는 간다
It's the circle of life
모두 살아가는
And it moves us all
끝이 없는 길
Through despair and hope
고난이 와도
Through faith and love
함께하면
Till we find our place
언젠간 우리
On the path unwinding
낙원을 찾겠지
In the circle
희망 안고
The circle of life
우리는 간다
Life's not fair, is it?
세상은 불공평해, 그렇지?
You see, I... Well, I shall never be king.
난 절대 왕이 될 수 없고
And you shall never see the light of another day.
년 다신 햇빛을 못 볼 테니까
Didn't your mother ever tell you not to play with your food?
먹을 거 갖고 장난치면 안 된다는 것도 몰라요?
What do you want?
무슨 일이냐?
I'm here to announce that King Mufasa's on his way,
무파사 대왕께서 납실 테니까
so you'd better have a good excuse for missing this morning's ceremony.
예식에 불참한 그럴듯한 핑켓거리가 있어야 할 겁니다
Oh, look, Zazu.
자주
You've made me lose my lunch.
너 때문에 점심거릴 놓쳤어
You'll lose more than that when the king gets through with you.
그게 문제예요?
He's as mad as a hippo with a hernia.
대왕님께서 얼마나 화나셨는지 알아요?
I quiver with fear!
이런 무서워서 벌벌 떨리네
Now, Scar, don't look at me that way.
스카, 그런 눈으로 바라보지 말아요
Help!
도와줘요!
Scar?
스카!
Drop him.
밸어라
Impeccable timing, Your Majesty.
절묘한 시간에 오셨습니다
Why, if it isn't my big brother descending from on high
하늘 같으신 폐하께서 이 미천한 동생을
to mingle with the commoners.
찾아오시다니요?
Sarabi and I didn't see you at the presentation of Simba.
심바의 후계자 명명식에 네가 안 보이더구나
That was today?
그게 오늘이었나?
I feel simply awful!
이런 실수가 다 있나!
Must've slipped my mind.
깜빠 잊었지 뭐유!
Yes, well, as slippery as your mind is,
명색이 삼촌인데
as the king's brother, you should've been first in line!
먼저 나서서 축하는 못해줄 망정
Well, I was first in line, until the little hairball was born.
난 그 애송이 때문에 서열 1위에서 밀려났어!
That hairball is my son and your future king.
그 애송이는 내 아들이자 왕의 후계자다
I shall practice my curtsy!
이런, 머리 조아리는 연습이나 해야지
Don't turn your back on me, Scar.
감히 내게 등을 돌리다니!
Oh, no, Mufasa.
설마요
Perhaps you shouldn't turn your back on me.
날 무시하다간 큰 코 다칠걸요
Is that a challenge?
도전하는 거냐?
Temper, temper.
성질도 급해라
I wouldn't dream of challenging you.
천만의 말씀에요
Pity. Why not?
과연 그럴까?
Well, as far as brains go, I got the lion's share.
지능으로 날 따라올
But when it comes to brute strength,
사자가 없지만
I'm afraid I'm at the shallow end of the gene pool.
싸움엔 영 소질이 없단 말이야
There's one in every family, sire.
집안마다 저런 애물단지가 하나씩은 있죠
Two in mine, actually,
경사 때마다
and they always manage to ruin special occasions.
찬물을 끼없는다니까요
What am I going to do with him?
저 녀석을 어떡한다?
He'd make a very handsome throw rug.
아예 발 깔개를 만들어.
Zazu!
자주!
And just think, whenever he gets dirty,
깔고 뭉개다가 더러워지면
you could take him out and beat him.
흠씬 두들겨 패는 거예요
Simba.
심바!
Dad! Dad!
아빠!
Come on, dad, we gotta go! Wake up!
어서 가야죠! 빨리 일어나세요!
Sorry.
미안
Dad! Dad!
아빠! 아빠!
Your son is awake.
당신 아들이 꺼요
Before sunrise, he's your son.
해 뜨기 전엔 당신 아들이야
Dad! Come on, Dad.
아빠, 어서요!
You promised.
약속했잖아요
Okay, Okay. I'm up, I'm up.
알았다, 일어날게
Yeah!
좋았어!
Look, Simba.
봐라, 심바
Everything the light touches is our kingdom.
햇빛이 달는 곳은 전부 우리의 영토다
Wow.
멋져요
A king's time as ruler rises and falls like the sun.
지도자인 왕도 태양처럼 뜨고 진단다
One day, Simba, the sun will set on my time here
언젠가 나의 시대는 가고
and will rise with you as the new king.
너의 시대가 올 것이다
-And this'll all be mine? -Everything.
- 이게 전부 내 것이 돼요? - 전부 다!
Everything the light touches.
빛이 달는 곳은 전부...
What about that shadowy place?
저쪽 그늘진 곳은요?
That's beyond our borders.
그곳은 경계 밖이다
You must never go there, Simba.
절대 가면 안 돼, 심바
But I thought a king can do whatever he wants.
왕은 뭐든 할 수 있는 줄 알았는데
Oh, there's more to being king than getting your way all the time.
왕에겐 권력보다 더 중요한 게 있다
-There's more? -Simba...
- 더 중요한 것? - 심바.…
Everything you see exists together in a delicate balance.
세상 모든 것은 미묘한 균형 속에 공존하고 있단다
As king, you need to understand that balance
왕은 이 균형을 이해하고
and respect all the creatures,
모든 생명을 존중해야 해
from the crawling ant to the leaping antelope.
조그만 개미부턴 커다란 들소까지.…
But, Dad, don't we eat the antelope?
하지만 우린 들소를 먹고 살잖아요
Yes, Simba, but let me explain.
그렇긴 하다만
When we die, our bodies become the grass,
우리가 죽어서 풀이 되면
and the antelope eat the grass.
들소는 그 풀을 먹지
And so we are all connected in the great circle of life.
결국 우린 모두 자연의 섭리 속에 사는 거란다
-Good morning, sire! -Good morning, Zazu.
- 일어나셨습니까, 전하! - 잘 자나, 자주?
Checking in with the morning report.
아침 보고를 드리겠습니다
Fire away.
시작하게
Well! The buzz from the bees
벌들이 난리를 쳤던 건
is that the leopards are in a bit of a spot.
표범 때문이었습니다
Really?
그래?
What are you doing, son?
뭘 하는 거냐?
Pouncing.
사냥이오
Let an old pro show you how it's done.
이 아빠가 한 수 가르쳐 주마
I told the elephants to forget it, but they can't...
코끼리가 찌르레기를 용서 못하겠답니다
-Zazu, would you turn around? -Yes, sire.
- 자주, 잠깐 돌아서 주겠나? - 물론이죠
The cheetahs are hard up, but...
치타들이 배고프다는데.
Stay low to the ground.
바닥에 낮게 드려라
Cheetahs never prosper...
남의 것을 뱃어먹으니.
Yeah, okay. Stay low to the ground, right? Yeah.
납작하게 잎드려서요
-What going on? -A pouncing lesson.
- 뭐 하시는 거죠? - 사냥 연습
Very good. Pouncing.
사냥이라.…
Pouncing? No, sire, you can't be serious...
사냥? 설마 진담은 아니시겠죠?
This is so humiliating.
아, 자존심 상해
Try not to make a sound.
숨소릴 죽이고.
What are you telling him, Mufasa?
뭐라고 하셨죠, 폐하?
Mufasa? Simba?
폐하? 심바?
That's very good.
아주 잘했다
-Zazu! -Yes!
- 자주! - 무슨 일이야?
-News from the underground. -Now, this time...
- 땅속 소식입니다 - 자, 이번엔.
Sire! Hyenas in the Pride Lands!
전하, 하이에나가 우리 땅에 왔답니다!
Zazu, take Simba home.
자주, 심바를 데리고 집에 가라
Dad, can't l come?
저도 가면 안 돼요?
No, son.
안 된다
I never get to go anywhere.
난 뭐든 못하게 해
Young master, one day, you will be king.
나중에 왕이 되시면
Then you can chase those slobbering, mangy, stupid poachers
그땐 저 더럽고 교활하고 멍청한 하이에나를
from dawn until dusk.
흠씬 혼내세요
Hey, Uncle Scar! Guess what?
스카 삼촌! 이거 아세요?
I despise guessing games.
알긴 뭘 알아?
I'm gonna be King of Pride Rock.
나중에 내가 왕이 된대요
Oh, goody!
좋겠다!
My dad just showed me the whole kingdom,
아빠가 왕국 전체를 보여줬어요
and I'm gonna rule it all!
내가 다스릴 거래요
Yes. Well, forgive me for not leaping for joy.
기뻐 날뛰지 못해 미안하구나
Bad back, you know.
허리가 아파서 말이야
Hey, Uncle Scar.
스카 삼촌!
When I'm king, what'll that make you?
내가 왕이 되면 삼촌은 뭐가 되죠?
A monkey's uncle.
원숭이 삼촌
-You're so weird. -You have no idea.
- 순 엉터리야 - 년 모를 거다
So, your father showed you the whole kingdom, did he?
아빠가 왕국 전체를 보여줬다고?
Everything.
전부 다요
He didn't show you what's beyond that rise at the northern border?
설마 북쪽 경계선까지 보여주진 않았겠지?
Well, no. He said I can't go there.
네, 거긴 가면 안 된대요
And he's absolutely right.
당연하지
It's far too dangerous.
거긴 용감한 사자 아니면
Only the bravest lions go there.
못 가는 곳이야
Well, I'm brave. What's out there?
나도 용감해요 뭐가 있는데요?
I'm sorry, Simba, I just can't tell you.
미안하다, 심바 말할 수 없어
Why not?
왜요?
I'm only looking out for the well-being of my favorite nephew.
내 소중한 조카를 위하는 마음 때문이지
Yeah, right! I'm your only nephew.
맞아요 하나밖에 없는 조카니까
All the more reason for me to be protective.
그러니 더 보살펴야 하지
An elephant graveyard is no place for a young prince. Oops!
코끼리 무덤 같은 곳은 왕자님이 갈 곳이 못 돼
An elephant what? Whoa!
코끼리 무덤?
Oh, dear, I've said too much.
이런, 안 할 말을 했군
Well, l suppose you'd have found out sooner or later,
하긴 넌 똑똑하니
you being so clever and all.
언젠가는 알아냈을 거야
Just do me one favor.
절대 그곳만은
Promise me you'll never visit that dreadful place.
가지 않겠다고 약속해주렴
No problem.
그럴게요
There's a good lad.
착하기도 해라
You run along now and have fun.
이제 그만 나가 놀아라
And remember,
지금 한 얘긴
it's our little secret.
비밀이란 거 잊지 마라
-Hey, Nala. -Hi, Simba.
- 날라! - 왜?
Come on. I just heard about this great place.
아주 굉장한 곳이 있어
Simba! I'm kind of in the middle of a bath.
심바 난 지금 목욕 중이야
And it's time for yours.
너도 해야지
Mom!
엄마!
Mom, you're messing up my mane!
내 갈기 다 엉켜요!
Okay, okay, I'm clean. Can we go now?
이제 깨끗하니까 가봐도 돼요?
So, where are we going?
어덜 가려고?
It better not be anyplace dumb.
시시한 곳이면 안 갈 거야
No, it's really cool.
아냐, 굉장한 곳이야
So, where is this really cool place?
그 굉장한 곳이 어디지?
-Around the water hole. -The water hole?
- 물웅덩이 근처요 - 물웅덩이?
What's so great about the water hole?
그게 뭐가 굉장해?
I'll show you when we get there.
가서 보여줄게
Mom, can I go with Simba?
엄마, 심바랑 가도 돼요?
What do you think, Sarabi?
보내도 될까요, 사라비?
Well...
글써.…
-Please?
- 제발요!
It's all right with me.
가도 괜찮겠지
-Yeah! -All right!
- 신 난다! - 좋았어!
As long as Zazu goes with you.
자주랑 함께 가도록 해
No, not Zazu.
그럼 안 되는데!
Step lively.
빨리 가요!
The sooner we get to the water hole, the sooner we can leave.
빨리 가야 빨리 돌아오죠
So, where are we really going?
사실은 어디 가는 거야?
An elephant graveyard.
코끼리 무덤!
Wow!
우와!
Zazu.
자주가 들어
Right. So, how are we gonna ditch the dodo?
저 촉새를 어떻게 따돌리지?
Just look at you two.
바야흐로 대초원에서
Little seeds of romance blossoming in the savanna.
하나의 로맨스가 쓰는구나
Your parents will be thrilled,
부모님이 얼마나 기뻐하실까
what with your being betrothed and all.
둘이 약혼하고.…
Be-what?
뭘 해요?
Betrothed. Intended.
약혼!
Affianced.
결혼을 약속하는 거예요
Meaning...
그래서요?
One day, you two are going to be married.
이 다음에 둘이 결혼하는 거죠
Yuck!
우웨!
I can't marry her. She's my friend.
어떻게 결혼해! 앤 내 친구인걸
Yeah, it'd be so weird.
맞아, 너무 웃긴다
Sorry to bust your bubble,
꿈을 깨서 미안하지만
but you two turtle doves have no choice.
두 분 맘대로 하는 게 아니에요
It's a tradition going back generations.
이건 조상 대대로 내려온 전통인걸요
When I'm king, that'll be the first thing to go.
내가 왕이 되면 그 전통부터 고칠 거야
-Not so long as I'm around. -Well, in that case, you're fired.
- 내가 있는 한 안 될걸요 - 그럼 널 해고시키지
Nice try, but only the king can do that.
누구 맘대로요! 그건 왕만이 할 수 있어요
Well, he's the future king.
심바가 왕이 될 거잖아
Yeah, so you have to do what I tell you.
그러니까 내가 시키는 대로 해
Not yet, I don't.
아직은 아니죠
And with an attitude like that,
지금 보아하니
I'm afraid you're shaping up to be a pretty pathetic king, indeed.
어째 좋은 왕이 될 것 같지 않네요
Not the way I see it.
내 생각은 달라
I'm gonna be a mighty king
나는 왕이 될 거야
So enemies beware
진짜 멋진 왕
Well, I've never seen a king of beasts
이렇게 갈기가 짧은 왕
With quite so little hair
나는 처음 봤어요
I'm gonna be the main event
나는 왕이 될 거야
Like no king was before
제일 좋은 왕
I'm brushin' up on lookin' down
의졌한 왕 되어서
I'm workin' on my roar
호령할 거야
Thus far, a rather uninspiring thing
무슨 일인지 심상치가 않아
Oh, I just can't wait to be king
어서 빨리 왕 되고파
You've rather a long way to go, young master, if you think...
아직 멀었어요 왕자님
-No one sayin’, "Do this" -Now, when ! said that...
- 그 누구도 내게 - 그러니까 내 말은.…
-No one saying, "Be there" -What I meant was...
- 명령하지 못해 - 무슨 뜻이냐면요.…
-No one sayin’, "Stop that" -You don't realize...
- 이렇게 하라고 - 내가 말할 기회를 전혀 안 주네
-No one sayin’, "See here" -Now, see here!
- 저렇게 하라고 - 얘기 좀 들어봐요!
Free to run around all day
하루 종일 놀아도 돼
Well, that's definitely out.
그것만은 안 될걸
Free to do it all my way
내 맘대로 할 거야!
[think it's time that you and!
저, 왕자님, 나하고
Arranged a heart-to-heart
애기 좀 합시다
Kings don't need advice
감히 누가
From little hornbills for a start
대왕님께 충고하느냐!
If this is where the monarchy is headed
오, 제멋대로 하려면
Count me out
제발 난 빼줘요
Out of service, out of Africa
버릇 없는 그런 아프리카
! wouldn't hang about
난 미련 없어요
This child is getting wildly out of wing
꼬마 왕자 정말 걱정돼
Oh, I just can't wait to be king
어서 빨리 왕 되고파
Everybody, look left
왼쪽을 봐도
Everybody, look right
오른쪽을 봐도
Everywhere you look, I'm
어느 곳을 봐도
Standing in the spotlight
내가 최고야
Not yet!
아직 아니거든!
Let every creature go for broke and sing
모두 즐겁게 노래해
Let's hear it in the herd and on the wing
자, 근심 걱정 떨쳐버리고
It's gonna be King Simba's finest fling
우리 심바 왕 정말 최고야!
Oh, I just can't wait to be king
나는 빨리 왕 되고파
Oh, I just can't wait
나는 빨리 왕..…
To be king
되고파
Il beg your pardon, madam, but
실례지만, 아줌마!
get off!
비켜 주세요!
Simba?
심바?
Nala!
날라!
All right! It worked!
좋아!
-We lost him. -lam a genius.
- 따돌렸어 - 난 천재라니까
Hey, genius, it was my idea.
계획 세운 건 나야
Yeah, but I pulled it off.
하지만 실천은 내가 했어
-With me! -Yeah?
- 나도 했어! - 그래?
-Pinned ya. -Hey, let me up!
- 내가 이겼지? - 비켜
Pinned ya again.
또 이겼다
This is it. We made it.
바로 여기였어
It's really creepy.
어째 으스스하다
Yeah.
그러네
Isn't it great?
굉장하지?
-We could get in big trouble. -l know!
- 혼날지도 몰라 - 알아!
l wonder if its brains are still in there.
뼈 안에 살이 남아 있을까?
There's only one way to know.
아는 방법은 하나뿐이야
Come on, let's go check it out.
가서 알아보자
Wrong! The only checking out you will do will be to check out of here.
아뇨! 가긴 어딜 갑니까? 어서 돌아가요!
Oh, man!
정말!
We're way beyond the boundary of the Pride Lands.
여긴 우리 영토를 한참 벗어난 곳이에요
Look, banana beak is scared.
이제 보니 순 겁쟁이네
It's Mr. banana beak to you, fuzzy,
겁쟁이래도 좋아요
and right now we are all in very real danger.
여긴 굉장히 위험해요
Danger?
위험?
l walk on the wild side.
얼마든지 오라고 해
I laugh in the face of danger.
비웃어 줄 테니까
Well, well, well, Banzai, what have we got here?
반자이, 이게 누구지?
I don't know, Shenzi.
모르겠는데, 센지
What do you think, Ed?
년 아니, 에드?
Just what I was thinking.
내 생각도 같아
Atrio of trespassers!
세 명의 무단 침입자!
And quite by accident, let me assure you.
실수로 들어온 거야
A simple navigational error.
방향을 잘못 잡아서 말이야
Whoa, whoa, wait, wait, wait.
잠깐, 잠깐!
I know you. You're Mufasa's little stooge.
이제 알았다 년 무파사의 앵무새구나
I], madam, am the king's major-domo.
난 대왕님의 비서관이오
And that would make you...
그렇다면 년...
The future king.
왕의 후계자다!
Do you know what we do to kings who step out of their kingdom?
왕이 왕국 밖으로 나오면 어떻게 되는지 알아?
You can't do anything to me.
감히 날 해치진 못할걸
Technically, they can. We are on their land.
해칠 수도 있어 여긴 재네 땅이니까
But you told me they're nothing but slobbering, mangy, stupid poachers.
하지만 하이에나는 더럽고 교활하고 멍청하잖아
Ix-nay on the upid-stay.
말을 가려서 해야지
-Who are you callin’ upid-stay? -My, my, my. Look at the sun!
- 우리가 더럽고 어째? - 이런, 해 좀 봐
-It's time to go! -What's the hurry?
- 돌아갈 시간이야! - 바 거 뭐 있어?
We'd love you to stick around for dinner.
저녁이나 먹고 가
Yeah, we could have whatever's lion around!
사자 반찬이 좋겠다
Wait, wait, wait, 1 got one, I got one!
잠깐, 좋은 생각이 있어
Make mine a cub sandwich! Whaddaya think?
난 샌드위치 해먹을래
What, Ed? What is it?
왜 그래, 에드? 뭐야?
Hey, did we order this dinner to go?
음식을 싸가지고 가서 먹을 거야?
No, why?
아니, 왜?
‘Cause there it goes!
도망치고 있으니까!
-Did we lose 'em? -I think so.
- 이젠 괜찮을까? - 그런 거 같아
Where's Zazu?
자주는 어덧지?
The little major-domo bird hippety-hopped
앵무새탕이나
all the way to the birdie-boiler.
끌여 먹어야지
No! Not the birdie-boiler!
제발 그것만은!
Hey, why don't you pick on somebody your own size?
치사하게 약한 새를 괴롭혀?
-Like you? -Oops.
- 그럼 네가 당해볼래? - 이런!
Simba!
심바!
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty.
꼬마 고양이야
That was it?
고작 그거냐?
Do it again. Come on.
다시 해봐, 어서
-Please, please! Uncle, uncle! -Silence!
- 아이고, 아저씨.… - 입 닥쳐!
-We're gonna shut up right now! -Calm down. We're really sorry.
- 입 다물게요 - 고정하세요, 죄송합니다
If you ever come near my son again...
다시 한번 내 아들 결에 얼씬거리면...
This is... This is your son?
아드님이세요?
-Your son. -Did you know that?
- 아들이구나 - 년 알고 있었니?
No. Me? I didn't know... No, did you?
아니, 난 몰랐어 년?
-No, of course not. -No.
- 물론 몰랐지 - 전혀
Ed?
에드?
Toodles.
도망쳐!
-Dad, I... -You deliberately disobeyed me.
- 아빠, 전.… - 년 내 명령을 거역했다
-Dad, I'm... I'm sorry. -Let's go home.
- 잘못했어요 - 집으로 가자
Il thought you were very brave.
난 네가 용감했다고 생각해
Zazu.
자주!
Yes, sire?
네, 폐하?
Take Nala home. I've got to teach my son a lesson.
날라를 데려다 줘라 아들 녀석을 혼내야겠다
Come, Nala.
가자, 날라
Simba, good luck.
심바, 행운을 빈다
Simba!
심바!
Simba, I'm very disappointed in you.
네게 실망했다
-l know. -You could've been killed.
- 알아요 - 넌 죽을 뻔했어
You deliberately disobeyed me,
명령을 거역하고
and what's worse, you put Nala in danger.
날라까지 위험에 빠뜨렸어
l was just trying to be brave, like you.
아빠쳐럼 용감해지고 싶었어요
I'm only brave when I have to be.
안 필요할 때만 용감해진단다
Simba, being brave
심바, 용기란.…
doesn't mean you go looking for trouble.
무모하게 부리는 게 아니야
But you're not scared of anything.
안 두려운 게 없으시잖아요
l was today.
아깐 두려웠다
-You were? -Yes.
- 그래요? - 그래
l thought I might lose you.
널 잃는 줄 알았어
I guess even kings get scared, huh?
왕도 무서울 때가 있군요?
-But you know what? -What?
- 그런데 있잖아요? - 뭐가?
I think those hyenas were even scareder.
하이에나는 아예 설설 기던데요
‘Cause nobody messes with your dad.
감히 이 아빠에게 까불 놈은 없지
-Come here, you. -No! No!
- 이리 와라 - 싫어요!
Gotcha!
잡았다!
Dad?
아빠?
-We're pals, right? -Right.
- 우린 친구죠? - 그래
And we'll always be together, right?
언제까지나 함께 있을 거죠?
Simba, let me tell you something that my father told me.
심바, 네 할아버지가 해주신 애기를 해주마
Look at the stars.
별들을 봐라
The great kings of the past look down on us from those stars.
돌아가신 선왕들이 우릴 지켜주고 계신 거란다
-Really? -Yes.
- 정말요? - 그래
So whenever you feel alone,
외로울 땐..
just remember that those kings will always be there to guide you.
널 지켜보는 선왕을 생각해라
And so will I.
나도 있을 테니까
Man, that lousy Mufasa. l won't be able to sit for a week.
망할 놈의 무파사! 일주일은 앉지도 못하겠어
It's not funny, Ed.
웃을 일이 아니야, 에드
Hey, shut up!
닥쳐!
Will you knock it off?
그만두지 못해!
-Well, he started it. -Look at you guys.
- 재가 시비 걸잖아 - 우리 꼴 좀 봐라
No wonder we're dangling at the bottom of the food chain.
남들 먹다 남은 찌꺼기만 먹고 사는 것도 당연하지
Man, I hate dangling.
찌꺼기는 이제 지겨워
Yeah? If it weren't for those lions, we'd be runnin’ the joint.
그놈의 사자만 없다면 우리가 호령하며 살 텐데
Man, I hate lions.
난 사자가 싫어
-So pushy. -And hairy.
- 거칠고 - 털 많고
-And stinky. -And, man, are they...
- 냄새나고 - 그리고.…
Ugly!
못생겼어!
Surely we lions are not all that bad.
사자가 그렇게 형편없진 않지
Scar. It's just you.
스카, 너구나
We were afraid it was somebody important.
난 또 무서운 사잔가 했지
Yeah, you know, like Mufasa.
무파사 같은 사자 말이야
-Yeah. -l see.
- 그렇지 - 그래?
-Now that's power! -Tell me about it.
- 정말 무서워 - 말도 마
I just hear that name and I shudder.
이름만 들어도 벌벌 떨린다니까
-Mufasa! -Do it again.
- 무파사! - 한번 더!
Mufasa!
무파사!
Mufasa! Mufasa! Mufasa!
무파사! 무파사!
It tingles me.
온몸이 굳는 것 같아
I'm surrounded by idiots.
멍청한 것들
Now, you, Scar, l mean, you're one of us. mean, you're our pal.
그럼 년 우리 친구니까 너도 멍청하겠네?
Charmed.
아이구 머리야
I like that. He's not king, but he's still so proper.
맘에 들어, 왕이 못 됐지만 품위는 있다니까
Yeah. Hey, did you bring us anything to eat,
혹시 먹을 것 좀 가져왔어?
Scar, old buddy, old pal? Huh? Did ya, did ya, did ya?
우리의 친구, 스카? 가져왔어?
I don't think you really deserve this.
밥값도 못하는 것들
I practically gift-wrapped those cubs for you,
갖다 바쳐도 사자 새끼 하나
and you couldn't even dispose of them.
처리 못하다니
Well, you know, it wasn't exactly like they was alone, Scar.
그게 혼자 온 게 아니더라고
Yeah. What were we supposed to do?
우린들 어쩌겠어?
Kill Mufasa?
무파사를 죽여?
Precisely.
바로 그거야
! know that your powers of retention
너희는 너무 미련하고
Are as wet as a warthog's backside
멕돼지처럼 둔하지만
But thick as you are, pay attention
자, 이번만은 정신차려
My words are a matter of pride
아주 중요한 일이야
It's clear from your vacant expressions
이 멍청한 표정을 보면
The lights are not all on upstairs
무슨 말인지 모르나 봐
But we're talking kings and successions
그러니까 왕을 없애자고
Even you can't be caught unawares
이제야 겨우 눈치채?
So prepare for the chance of a lifetime
지금 이 순간이 우리에겐
Be prepared for sensational news
일생일대의 기회잖아
A shiny new era is tiptoeing nearer
새로운 시대가 점점 다가온다
And where do we feature?
그러면 뭐가 달라져?
Just listen to teacher
우선 듣기나 해
! know it sounds sordid
솜 비겁하지만
But you'll be rewarded
일단 성공하면
When at last 1 am given my dues
내가 큰 상을 내려줄 거야
And injustice deliciously squared
이젠 드디어 내 시대가 온다
Be prepared
준비해라!
Yeah, be prepared. We'll be prepared. For what?
그래, 준비할게 그런데 뭘?
For the death of the king.
왕의 죽음을!
-Why, is he sick? -No, fool, we're going to kill him.
- 왜, 병들었어? - 우리가 죽이는 거야!
-And Simba, too. -Great idea. Who needs a king?
- 심바도 함께 - 좋은 생각이야, 왕은 필요 없어!
No king, no king
필요 없어, 랄라랄라랄라
-Idiots! There will be a king! -Hey, but you said...
- 머저리, 왕이 왜 없어! - 하지만 방금.…
I will be king!
내가 왕이 될 거야!
Stick with me,
나를 따르면
and you'll never go hungry again.
다신 굴주리지 않을 것이다
-Yeah! All right! -Long live the king!
- 그래, 왕이여 - 만수무강하소서!
Long live the king! Long live the king!
만수무강하소서!
It's great that we'll soon be connected
우리도 기를 펴보자
With a king who'll be all-time adored
저 새로운 왕 덕분에
Of course, quid pro quo you're expected
이번 일에서 실수하면
To take certain duties on board
너희 모두 각오해라
The future is littered with prizes
오, 미래는 우리들 차지
And though I'm the main addressee
내가 왕이 되기만 하면
The point that l must emphasize is
다시 한번 강조할 말씀
You won't get a sniff without me!
내게 절대 복종해
So prepare for the coup of the century
역사상 최대의 큰 음모가
Be prepared for the murkiest scam
세상의 빛을 보게 된다
Meticulous planning
이 치밀한 계획
Tenacity spanning
이 뛰어난 머리
Decades of denial
날 따를 자 누가
ls simply why I'll be king undisputed
있으면 나와봐 나 존경을 받고
Respected, saluted
나 전지전능한
And seen for the wonder! am
최고의 왕 될 거야
Yes, my teeth and ambitions are bared
이제 우리의 미래를 위해
Be prepared
준비해!
Yes, our teeth and ambitions are bared
이제 우리의 승리를 위해
You wait here. Your father has a marvelous surprise for you.
여기 있어, 아빠가 깜짝 선물을 주신단다
What is it?
그게 뭔데요?
If l told you, it wouldn't be a surprise now, would it?
그걸 말하면 깜짝 선물이 아니지
If you tell me, I'll still act surprised.
놀라는 척할게요
You are such a naughty boy.
이런 장난꾸러기!
-Come on, Uncle Scar. -No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
- 제발요, 스카 삼촌 -안돼
This is just for you and your daddy.
이건 너와 네 아빠 사이의 일이야
You know, a sort of father-son thing.
부자간의 정이랄까
Well, I'd better go get him.
난 그만 가봐야겠다
-I'll go with you. -No.
- 같이 가요 - 아니!
No. Just stay on this rock.
여기 꼼짝 말고 있어
You wouldn't want to end up in another mess
하이에나 소동처럼
like you did with the hyenas.
또 망 피울 생각은 없겠지?
-You know about that? -Simba, everybody knows about that.
- 알고 계셨어요? - 소문이 짝 퍼졌단다
-Really? -Yes.
- 그래요? - 아무렴
Lucky daddy was there to save you, eh?
다행히 아빠가 나타나서 구해주셨다면서?
And just between us,
그럼 그동안
you might want to work on that little roar of yours, hmm?
소리 지르는 거나 연습하고 있으렴
Okay.
알았어요
Hey, Uncle Scar, willl like this surprise?
스카 삼촌! 좋은 선물이에요?
Simba, it's to die for.
좋아서 죽을 거다
Shut up.
조용히 해!
I can't help it. I'm so hungry. I got to have a wildebeest.
얼 수가 없어, 배고파 죽겠어 영양 하나만 잡아먹자
Stay put.
가만있어
Can't I just pick off one of the little sick ones?
작은 놈 하나만 잡아올게
No. We wait for the signal from Scar.
안돼 스카의 신호를 기다려야 해
There he is. Let's go.
신호다! 가자!
"Little roar."
소리 연습?
Look, sire, the herd is on the move.
전하, 짐승 떼가 이동합니다
-Odd. -Mufasa, quick.
- 심상찮군 - 형님, 큰일이에요
Stampede in the gorge.
골짜기에 영양 떼가.…
-Simba's down there! -Simba?
- 심바가 거기 있어요! - 심바가?
Zazu, help me!
자주, 살려줘!
Your father is on the way! Hold on!
대왕님이 오시니까 조금만 참아
Hurry!
서둘러!
There! There on that tree!
저기 나무 위에요!
Hold on, Simba!
기다려라, 심바!
Dad!
아빠!
Scar, this is awful!
스카, 이럴 수가!
What'll we do? What'll we do?
어쩌면 좋지?
I'll go back for help, that's what I'll do.
돌아가서 도움을 청해야지! 내가 할 일은 도움을...
Dad!
아빠!
Scar!
스카!
-Brother. -Brother, help me!
아우야, 도와다오!
Long live the king.
왕이여, 만수무강 하소서
No!
안 돼!
Dad!
아빠!
Dad?
아빠?
Dad, come on.
아빠, 어서요
You got to get up.
일어나세요
Dad?
아빠?
We got to go home.
집에 가야죠
Help!
도와줘요!
Somebody!
아무도 없어요?
Anybody.
누구든지..…
Help.
도와줘요!
Simba. What have you done?
심바, 어떻게 된 거냐?
There were wildebeests, and he tried to save me.
영양 떼가 와서 날 구하려다.…
It was an accident. I didn't mean for it to happen.
사고였어요 난 이럴 줄 몰랐어요
Of course. Of course you didn't.
알고 그랬을 리야 없지
No one ever means for these things to happen.
아무도 알고 그런 짓을 하진 않아
But the king is dead.
하지만 왕이 돌아가셨다
And if it weren't for you, he'd still be alive.
네가 아니었으면 돌아가시지 않았어
What will your mother think?
엄마가 알면 뭐라실까?
What am I going to do?
어쩌면 좋죠?
Run away, Simba.
도망가, 심바
Run. Run away and never return.
도망가서 다신 돌아오지 마
Kill him.
없애!
Hey, there he goes. There he goes.
저기 간다!
So go get him.
가서 없애!
There ain't no way I'm going in there.
미쳤냐, 저길 가게?
What, you want me to come out looking like you, cactus butt?
너쳐럼 선인장 끌이 되라고?
But we got to finish the job.
임무는 완수해야지
Well, he's as good as dead out there anyway.
어차피 죽은 거나 같아
And if he comes back, we'll kill him.
돌아오면 그때 죽이지 뭐
Yeah! You hear that?
너도 들었지?
If you ever come back, we'll kill you!
돌아오면 죽여버릴 거야!
Mufasa's death is a terrible tragedy.
무파사의 죽음은 엄청난 비극입니다
But to lose Simba, who had barely begun to live...
더구나 어린 심바마저 실종되었습니다
For me, itis a deep, personal loss.
이제 침통한 마음으로
So it is with a heavy heart that l assume the throne.
왕위를 계승합니다
Yet out of the ashes of this tragedy we shall rise
우린 이 비극을 덮고 일어나
to greet the dawning of a new era
새 시대를 열어야 합니다
in which lion and hyena come together
번영과 평화를 위해
in a great and glorious future.
사자와 하이에나는 함께 살 것이다!
Get out! Get out! Get out of here!
비켜, 꺼지란 말이야!
I love this! Bowling for buzzards.
말똥가리 볼링은 정말 재밌어
Gets 'em every time.
스트레스가 확 풀리지
Hey, Timon, you better come look.
티몬, 이리 와서 봐
I think it's still alive.
아직 살아있어
All righty, what have we got here?
이게 뭐야?
Jeez, it's a lion! Run, Pumbaa, move it!
사자잖아! 도망쳐, 품바! 어서!
Hey, Timon, it's just a little lion.
새끼 사잔데 뭘
Look at him. He's so cute and all alone.
너무 귀여워 혼자인가 봐
-Can we keep him? -Pumbaa, are you nuts?
- 우리가 기를까? - 정신 나갔어?
You're talking about a lion. Lions eat guys like us.
애는 사자야 사자는 우리 천적이야
-But he's so little. -He's going to get bigger.
- 하지만 어리잖아 - 금방 커질 거야
Maybe he'll be on our side.
우리 편이 될지도 몰라
That's the stupidest thing l ever heard. Maybe he'll...
오래 살다 보니 별소릴 다 듣겠네
Hey, I've got it. What if he's on our side?
잠깐만! 우리 편?
You know, having a lion around might not be such a bad idea.
사자랑 같이 다녀서 손해 볼 건 없겠는데
So we're keeping him?
그럼 기를 거지?
Of course. Who's the brains of this outfit?
물론, 누가 대장을 하지?
My point exactly.
내가 맡지 뭐
Jeez, I'm fried. Let's get out of here and find some shade.
날이 덤다 그늘을 찾아가자
-You okay, kid? -l guess so.
- 정신이 드니? - 그런가 봐
You nearly died.
년 죽을 뻔했어
I saved you.
내가 구했지
Well, Pumbaa helped. A little.
품바도 도왔지만. 찌금!
Thanks for your help.
살려줘서 고마워
Hey, where you going?
어딜 가는 거야?
Nowhere.
아무 데나
Gee, he looks blue.
우거지상이네
-I'd say brownish gold. -No, no, no. 1 mean he's depressed.
- 내가 보기엔 사자상인걸 - 우울해 보인다고
Kid, what's eating you?
무슨 속상한 일 있니?
Nothing. He's at the top of the food chain.
동물의 왕 사자신데 그럴 리가 있나
The food chain!
동물의 왕이라..…
So, where you from?
어디 출신이야?
Who cares? I can't go back.
묻지 마 돌아갈 수도 없어
You're an outcast. That's great. So are we.
쫓겨났구나? 잘됐네, 우리도 같은 쳐지야
-What'd you do, kid? -Something terrible.
- 왜 쫓겨났니? - 괴로운 일이라
-But I don't want to talk about it. -We don't want to hear about it.
- 말하고 싶지 않아 - 우리도 듣고 싶지 않아
Come on, Timon. Anything we can do?
도와줄 일은 없어?
Not unless you can change the past.
과거를 되돌린다면 모를까.
You know, kid, in times like this, my buddy Timon here says,
이럴 때 티몬이 하는 말이 있어
"You got to put your behind in your past."
'과거를 물어주세요!"
No, no, no.
그게 아니지
-[ mean... -Amateur.
- 그러니까.… - 제대로 하는 게 없어
Lie down before you hurt yourself.
힘들 텐데 좀 앉아
It's, "You got to put your past behind you."
원래는 '과거를 잊어주세요'야
Look, kid, bad things happen, and you can't do anything about it, right?
과거는 흘러갔고 얼 수 없는 거야, 그렇지?
-Right. -Wrong!
- 그래 - 좋아!
When the world turns its back on you,
세상이 널 힘들게 할 땐
you turn your back on the world.
신경 끄고 사는 게 상책이야
Well, that's not what I was taught.
난 그렇게 배우지 않았는데
Then maybe you need a new lesson.
선생을 잘못 만난 게지
Repeat after me.
날 따라해 봐
-Hakuna matata. -What?
- 하쿠나 마타타 - 뭐?
Hakuna matata.
하쿠나 마타타
It means "no worries".
걱정 말라는 뜻이야
What a wonderful phrase.
정말 멋진 말이지!
Hakuna matata.
하쿠나 마타타
Ain't no passing craze
끝내주는 말씀
It means no worries
근심과 걱정
For the rest of your days
모두 떨쳐 버려
It's our problem-free philosophy
욕심 버리면 즐거워져
Hakuna matata
하쿠나 마타타
Hakuna matata?
하쿠나 마타타?
-Yeah. It's our motto. -What's a motto?
- 우리 신조야 - 신조가 뭐야?
Nothin’. What's-a-motto with you?
글써, 네 신조는 뭐지?
You know, kid, these two words will solve all your problems.
이 여섯 글자만 있으면 만사가 해결돼
That's right. Take Pumbaa, for example. Why...
품바 얘길 해줄게
When he was a young warthog
이 친구가 어렸을 때
When I was a young warthog
내가 아주 어렸을 때
-Very nice. -Thanks.
- 잘했어 - 고마워
He found his aroma lacked a certain appeal
밥을 먹고 나면 모두 도망갔어
He could clear the savanna after every meal
그의 트림 냄새가 너무 지독해서
I'ma sensitive soul
미련해 보여도
Though I seem thick-skinned
예민하단 말이야
And it hurt that my friends never stood downwind
얼마나 속이 상했는지 몰라
-And, oh, the shame -He was ashamed
- 너무 창피해 - 오, 너무 창피해
-Thought of changing my name -Oh, what's in a name?
- 이름을 바겠지 - 바꾼다고 되나
And I got downhearted
너무 실망해서
-How did you feel? -Every time that...
- 그럴 만도 해! - 그 다음부터 난.…
-Hey, not in front of the kids. -Oh, sorry.
- 애 앞에서 무슨 소리야? - 이런, 미안!
Hakuna matata
하쿠나 마타타!
What a wonderful phrase
정말 멋진 말이지
Ain't no passing craze
끝내주는 말씀
It means no worries
근심과 걱정
For the rest of your days
모두 떨쳐버려
Yeah, sing it, kid.
따라 불러
It's our problem-free
욕심 버리면
Philosophy
즐거워요
Hakuna matata
하쿠나 마타타
Welcome to our humble home.
조라한 우리 집에 오신 걸 환영합니다
-You live here? -We live wherever we want.
- 여기 살아? - 살고 싶은 데서 살지
Yep. Home is where your rump rests.
정들면 고향인 거야
It's beautiful.
아름다워
I'm starved.
배고픈걸
I'm so hungry I could eat a whole zebra.
지금 같아선 얼룩말도 통째로 삼키겠어
We're fresh out of zebra.
얼룩말은 떨어졌는데
Any antelope?
들소는?
-Hippo? -Nope.
- 하마? - 없어
Listen, kid, if you live with us, you have to eat like us.
우리랑 살려면 식생활부더 바꿔야 해
Hey, this looks like a good spot to rustle up some grub.
여기에 땅벌레가 많겠는걸
What's that?
그게 뭐야?
A grub. What's it look like?
땅벌레지, 뭐긴 뭐야?
Gross.
육, 징그러
Tastes like chicken.
닭고기 맛이야
Slimy yet satisfying.
근적거리긴 해도 맛은 좋아
These are rare delicacies.
섬세한 이 맛!
Piquant, with a very pleasant crunch.
이건 아삭아삭 썸히는 맛이 일품이지
You'll learn to love them.
먹을수록 맛있어
I'm telling you, kid, this is the great life,
여긴 규칙도 책임도 없어
no rules, no responsibilities.
멋지게 살 수 있어
The little cream-filled kind.
속에 크림이 들었네
And best of all, no worries.
걱정이 없다는 게
Well, kid?
제일 좋아
Oh, well. Hakuna matata.
하쿠나 마타타
Slimy, yet satisfying.
근적거리지만 먹을 만해
That's it.
그럼 됐어
Hakuna matata
하쿠나 마타타
-Hakuna... -lt means no worries
- 하쿠나. - 근심과 걱정
For the rest of your days
모두 떨쳐버려
It's our problem-free
욕심 버리면
Philosophy
즐거워요
Hakuna matata
하쿠나 마타타
Nobody knows
아무도 아픔
The trouble I've seen
모른다네
My sorrow
몰라
Zazu, do lighten up.
자주, 신나는 것 좀 해라
Sing something with a little bounce in it.
방방 뜨는 걸로 좀 해
It's a small world after all
온 세상의 어린이
No, no! Anything but that!
그만! 그건 부르지 마
I've got a lovely bunch of coconuts
시원한 열대 과일 코코
Deedle dee dee
디덜리디디
There they are a-standing in a row
나무 위에 줄줄이 줄줄
Big ones, small ones, some as big as your head
큰 거, 작은 거 아주 맛있겠네
I would never have had to do this with Mufasa.
무파사 왕은 이런 건 안 시켰는데
What? What did you say?
뭐라고 했지?
-Nothing. -You know the law.
- 아무것도 아네요 - 내 앞에선
Never, ever mention that name in my presence. I am the king!
그 이름 말하지 마 내가 왕이야!
Yes, sire, you are the king.
네, 폐하 왕이시고 말고요
I... Lonly mentioned it to illustrate the differences
다만 통치 방법의 차이를
in your royal managerial approaches.
말한 것뿐이에요
-Hey, boss. -What is it this time?
- 이봐요, 대장! - 이번엔 뭐냐?
-We got a bone to pick with you. -I'll handle this.
- 할 얘기가 있어요 - 내가 말할게
Scar, there's no food, no water.
먹을 것도 마실 것도 없어요
Yeah. It's dinner time and we ain't got no stinking entrées.
저녁 시간인데 목 축일 것도 없다고요
It's the lionesses' job to do the hunting.
사냥은 암사자의 책임이야
Yeah, but they won't go hunt.
안 하니까 문제죠
-Eat Zazu. -You wouldn't want me.
- 앵무새라도 먹어 - 난 맛 없어요
I'd be so tough and gamey and...
살도 없고 질기기만 해요
Zazu, don't be ridiculous. All you need is a little garlic.
양념만 좀 치면 괜찮을걸
I thought things were bad under Mufasa.
무파사 시절이 좋았어
-What did you say? -l said Muf...
- 뭐라고 했지? - 그러니까 무파.…
lsaid qué pasa?
엘콘도르 파사요
Good. Now get out.
좋아, 그만 가봐
But we're still hungry.
하지만 배가 고파요
Out!
꺼져!
-Whoa! Nice one, Simba. -Thanks.
- 멋진데, 심바? - 고마워
-Man, I'm stuffed. -Me, too.
- 아, 배부르다 - 나도
l ate like a pig.
돼지처럼 먹었어
Pumbaa, you are a pig.
품바, 넌 돼지야
Right.
그렇군
-Timon? -Yeah?
- 티몬? - 음?
Ever wonder what those sparkling dots are up there?
하늘에 반짝이는 게 뭔지 궁금하지 않니?
Pumbaa, I don't wonder, I know.
아니, 안 궁금해 난 아니까
What are they?
뭔데?
They're fireflies.
반덧불이야
Fireflies that got stuck up in that big blueish-black thing.
반덧붙이 검은 융단에 콕콕 박혀 있는 거야
Gee.
그렇구나
l always thought they were balls of gas
난 아주 먼 곳에 있는
burning billions of miles away.
가스 덩어린 줄 알았지
Pumbaa, with you, everything's gas.
품바, 너한텐 모든 게 가스겠지
Simba, what do you think?
심바, 넌 어떻게 생각해?
Well, don't know.
난 몰라
Come on. Give, give, give, give.
어서 말해봐
Come on. We told you ours. Please?
우리도 말했잖아 부탁해요
Well...
그럼...
Somebody once told me
들은 얘긴데
that the great kings of the past are up there watching over us.
돌아가신 선왕이 우릴 지켜주는 거래
Really?
그래?
You mean a bunch of royal dead guys are watching us?
죽은 귀신들이 우릴 내려다보고 있단 말이야?
-Who told you something like that? -Yeah, yeah.
- 어떤 놈이 그랬어? - 그러게
-What mook made that up? -Yeah. Pretty dumb, huh?
- 어떤 얼간이가 그래? - 바보 같지, 그렇지?
-You're killing me. -Yeah.
- 배꼽 빠지겠다 - 맞아
Was it something I said?
내가 말실수를 했나?
Simba?
심바?
He's... He's alive? He's alive!
살아 있어? 살아 있었어!
It is time.
때가 왔어
In the jungle, the mighty jungle
넓은 정글 저 험한 정글
The lion sleeps tonight
오, 사자가 잔다
The lion sleeps to...
오, 사자가 잔다
Il can't hear you, buddy. Back me up.
소리가 작다 크게 해!
Pumbaa? Pumbaa?
품바?
Timon?
티몬?
Pumbaa! Pumbaa!
품바! 품바!
Pumbaa, Pumbaa! Hey, what's going on?
품바! 무슨 일이야?
She's going to eat me!
날 잡아 먹겠대!
Whoa! Jeez, why do I always have to save your...
꼭 급할 때만 날 찾아요
Don't worry, buddy. I'm here for you. Everything's going to be okay.
걱정 마, 내가 있잖아 이젠 괜찮아
Get her! Bite her head!
곽 물어버려!
Go for the jugular! The jugular!
인정사정 볼 거 없어!
See, I told you he'd come in handy.
언젠가 쓸모 있을 거랬지?
Nala?
날라?
Is it really you?
정말 너야?
-Who are you? -It's me. Simba.
- 누구세요? - 나야, 심바
Simba?
심바?
Whoa! How did you...
아니, 어떻게.
-Wow! -Where did you come from?
- 세상에! - 어디서 나타난 거야?
This is gr... It's great to see you!
정말 반갑다!
-Hey, what's goin’ on here? -What are you doing here?
- 어찌된 일이야? - 여기까지 엔일이야?
What am I doing here? What are you doing here?
나보고 원일이냐고? 넌 여기서 뭐 해?
Hey! What's goin’ on here?
어떻게 된 거야?
Timon, this is Nala. She's my best friend.
티몬, 여긴 내 친구인 날라야
-Friend? -Yeah. Hey, Pumbaa, come over here.
- 친구? - 품바, 이쪽으로 와
Nala, this is Pumbaa. Pumbaa, Nala.
날라, 얘는 품바야 품바, 날라야
-Pleased to make your acquaintance. -The pleasure is all mine.
- 만나서 무지 반가워요 - 마찬가지예요
How do you... Whoa, whoa! Time out! Let me get this straight.
잠깐! 질고 넘어갈 게 있어
You know her, she knows you.
넌 져 아가씨를 알고 저 아가씨도 널 알아
But she wants to eat him, and everybody's okay with this?
저 아가씬 품바를 먹으려 했는데 그래도 되는 거야?
-Did I miss something? -Relax, Timon.
- 내가 모르는 게 있는 거야? - 진정해, 티몬
Wait till everyone finds out you've been here all this time.
네가 여기 있는 걸 알면 모두 놀랄 거야
And your mother, what will she think?
너희 엄마가 아시면 뭐라실까?
She doesn't have to know. Nobody has to know.
엄마는 모르셔도 돼 아무도 알 필요 없어
Of course they do. Everyone thinks you're dead.
당연히 알아야지 모두 네가 죽은 줄 알아
They do?
그래?
Yeah. Scar told us about the stampede.
네가 깔려 죽었다고 스카가 말했어
He did? What else did he tell you?
그래? 또 무슨 말을 했지?
What else matters? You're alive. And that means, you're the king.
살아 있는데 무슨 상관이야 이제 넌 왕이 돼야 해
King? Lady, have you got your lions crossed!
왕? 아가씨 제정신이 아니시군요
King?
왕이란 말이지?
Your Majesty, I gravel at your feet.
폐하! 황공 무지개로소이다
-Stop it. -It's not gravel, it's grovel.
- 그만해 - 무지개가 아니라 무지로소이다야
And don't! He's not the king. Are you?
왕도 아닌데 뭐 왕 맞아?
-No. -Simba!
- 아니 - 심바!
No, I'm not the king. Maybe I was gonna be,
난 왕이 아니야 그럴 뻔했었지만
but that was a long time ago.
오래 전 얘기야
Let me get this straight. You're the king? And never told us?
그럼 네가 왕이었단 걸 여태껏 말 안 한 거야?
-Look, I'm still the same guy. -But with power.
- 난 달라진 거 없어 - 권력이 있지!
Could you guys excuse us for a few minutes?
잠깐 자리 좀 피해주겠어?
Hey, whatever she has to say,
할 말 있으면
she can say in front of us, right, Simba?
우리 있는 데서 말해 그렇지, 심바?
Maybe you'd better go.
비켜주면 좋겠어
It starts. You think you know a guy.
벌써 변하기 시작했어
Timon and Pumbaa, you learn to love 'em.
티몬하고 품바 너도 좋아하게 될 거야
What?
왜 그래?
What is it?
뭐야?
It's like you're back from the dead.
네가 죽었다 살아 돌아온 것 같아
You don't know how much this will mean to everyone.
네가 살아 있다는 게 무슨 의미인지 아니?
What it means to me.
특히 내겐.…
-Hey, it's okay. -I've really missed you.
- 이러지 마 - 네가 보고 싶었어
I've missed you, too.
나도 보고 싶었어
I tell you, Pumbaa. This stinks.
뭔가 냄새가 나지?
Sorry.
미안해
Not you! Them!
너 말고, 저 애들
Him, her, alone.
여자랑 단둘이
What's wrong with that?
그게 뭐가 어때서
-l can see what's happening -What?
- 눈만 봐도 알아 - 뭘?
-And they don't have a clue -Who?
- 사랑에 빠진 거야 - 누가?
They'll fall in love and here's the bottom line
그렇게 되면 친구도 몰라봐
Our trio's down to two
우리 둘만 남겠지
The sweet caress of twilight
너무나 달콤해서
There's magic everywhere
정신이 몽롱해져
And with all this romantic atmosphere
아, 이렇게도 낭만적인데
Disaster's in the air
왜 눈물이 날까
Can you feel the love tonight?
사랑으로 가득한
The peace the evening brings
이 밤을 느껴요
The world for once
눈부시게
In perfect harmony
새로운 미래가
With all its living things
펼쳐지고 있어
So many things to tell her
이 설레이는 마음
But how to make her see
어떻게 전하나
The truth about my past?
고백을 해볼까?
Impossible, she'd turn away from me
오, 안 돼! 용기가 안 나네
He's holding back, he's hiding
왜 망설이게 될까?
But what, I can't decide
알 수 없는 마음
Why won't he be the king I know he is?
언제나 그를 사랑했지만
The king l see inside?
말을 못하겠어
Can you feel the love tonight?
사랑으로 가득한
The peace the evening brings
이 밤을 느껴요
The world for once
눈부시게
In perfect harmony
새로운 미래가
With all its living things
펼쳐지고 있어
Can you feel the love tonight?
사랑스러운 이 밤
You needn't look too far
눈으로 말해요
Stealing through
바라보는
The night's uncertainties
그대의 눈 속에
Love is where they are
내가 있으니
And if he falls in love tonight
만일 그들이 사랑에
It can be assumed
빠져버리면
His carefree days
그 즐겁던
With us are history
시절은 가고
In short, our pal
슬픔만
ls doomed
남겠죠
Isn't this a great place?
멋진 곳이지?
It is beautiful.
아름다워
But I don't understand something.
하지만 궁금한 게 있어
You've been alive all this time.
살아 있었으면서
Why didn't you come back to Pride Rock?
왜 고향으로 안 돌아온 거야?
Well, I just needed to get out on my own, live my own life.
독립해서 혼자 살고 싶었어
And I did, and it's great.
얼마나 좋은데!
We've really needed you at home.
우린 네가 필요해
-No one needs me. -Yes, we do. You're the king.
- 난 무용지물이야 - 필요해, 년 우리 왕이야
Nala, we've been through this. I'm not the king. Scar is.
날라, 지나간 일이야 내가 아니라 스카가 왕이야
Simba, he let the hyenas take over the Pride Lands.
심바, 스카가 하이에나를 끌어들였어
-What? -Everything's destroyed.
- 뭐? - 모든 게 파괴됐어
There's no food, no water.
먹을 것도 물도 없어
Simba, if you don't do something soon, everyone will starve.
뭔가 조치를 안 취하면 우린 굴어죽고 말아
-l can't go back. -Why?
- 난 돌아갈 수 없어 - 어째서?
-You wouldn't understand. -What?
- 년 이해 못해 - 뭘 이해 못해?
No, no, no. It doesn't matter. Hakuna matata.
이젠 상관없어 하쿠나 마타타
-What? -Hakuna matata.
- 뭐? - 하쿠나 마타타
It's something I learned out here. Sometimes bad things happen...
여기서 배운 거야 나쁜 일이 일어나도
Simba...
심바!
..and there's nothing you can do about it. So why worry?
손쓸 방법이 없을 땐 내버려 둘 수밖에
-Because it's your responsibility. -Well, what about you? You left.
- 이건 너의 책임이야 - 년? 너도 떠났잖아
I left to find help, and I found you.
도움을 청하러 나온 거야 그래서 널 찾았고
Don't you understand? You're our only hope.
그래도 모르겠어? 너만이 우리 희망이야
-Sorry. -What's happened to you?
- 미안해 - 왜 이렇게 변했지?
-You're not the Simba I remember. -You're right. I'm not.
- 내가 알던 심바가 아니야 - 그래, 난 변했어
-Now are you satisfied? -No. Just disappointed.
- 이제 만족하니? - 아니, 실망했을 뿐이야
You know, you're starting to sound like my father.
꼭 내 아버지쳐럼 말하는구나
Good. At least one of us does.
나라도 닮았다니 다행이다
You think you can just show up and tell me how to live my life?
네가 뭔데 이래라저래라 명령이야?
You don't even know what I've been through.
내가 어떻게 살아 왔는지 알기나 해?
l would if you'd just tell me.
말을 해야 알지
-Forget it! -Fine!
- 그만뒤 - 좋아!
She's wrong. I can't go back.
날라가 틀렸어 난 돌아갈 수 없어
What would it prove, anyway? It won't change anything.
설령 가면 뭐 해? 달라질 건 없어
You can't change the past.
과거는 돌이킬 수 없어
You said you'd always be there for me!
아버진 늘 절 지켜주신대?
But you're not.
그런데 아니었어요
And it's because of me.
전부 나 때문이야
It's my fault.
내 잘못이야
Come on, will you cut it out?
그만 좀 해
Can't cut it out. It'll grow right back!
그만둘 수가 없어 완전 자동이거든
Creepy little monkey. Will you stop following me?
재수 없는 원숭이 따라오지 마
-Who are you? -The question is, who are you?
- 년 누구야? - 그보다 년 누구야?
I thought I knew. Now I'm not so sure.
아는 줄 알았는데 이젠 모르겠어
Well, l know who you are. Come here. It's a secret.
난 네가 누군지 알지 이리와, 비밀을 말해줄게
Enough! What is that supposed to mean?
충분히 들었어 그게 무슨 뜻이지?
It means you are a baboon, and I'm not.
년 원숭이고 난 아니라는 뜻
I think you're a little confused.
정신이 나간 모양이군
Wrong! I'm not the one who's confused.
틀렸어! 정신 나간 건 바로 너야
-You don't even know who you are. -And I suppose you know.
- 년 네 자신이 누군지도 몰라 - 년 안단 말이지?
Sure do. You're Mufasa's boy.
알고 말고 년 무파사의 아들이야
-Bye. -Hey, wait!
- 잘 있어 - 기다려!
You knew my father?
우리 아버지를 아셨어요?
Correction, I know your father.
틀렸어 난 네 아버지를 알아
I hate to tell you this,
안된 얘기지만
but he died a long time ago.
오래 전에 돌아가셨어요
Nope. Wrong again!
또 틀렸어!
He's alive, and I'll show him to you.
그분은 살아 계셔 내가 보여줄게
You follow old Rafiki. He knows the way. Come on!
이 라피키를 따라와 내가 길을 알아, 가자!
Don't dawdle. Hurry up!
빨리 와!
-Hey, whoa, wait, wait. -Come on. Come on!
- 기다려요! - 어서!
Would you slow down?
솜 천천히 가요!
Stop!
정지!
Look down there.
이 아래로 내려가 봐
That's not my father. That's just my reflection.
이건 아버지가 아니야 내 그림자지
No.
아니
Look harder.
더 자세히 봐
You see?
보이지?
He lives in you.
아버진 네 안에 살아 계셔
Simba.
심바
Father?
아버지?
Simba, you have forgotten me.
심바, 년 날 잊었구나
No. How could I?
제가 어떻게 잊겠어요?
You have forgotten who you are, and so have forgotten me.
너 자신을 잊는 건 바로 이 아비를 잊는 것
Look inside yourself, Simba.
너의 마음을 들여다 봐라
You are more than what you have become.
지금은 년 네가 아니다
You must take your place in the circle of life.
자연의 섭리에 따라야 한다
How can I go back? I'm not who I used to be.
어떻게 돌아가죠? 전 예전의 제가 아니에요
Remember who you are.
너 자신을 기억해라
You are my son and the one true king.
년 나의 아들이자 진정한 왕이다
No! Please, don't leave me!
제발, 가지 마세요!
Remember.
기억하거라
-Father! -Remember!
- 아버지! - 기억해라!
Don't leave me.
가지 마세요
Remember.
기억해라
What was that?
방금 뭐가 지나갔지?
The weather.
날씨 한번 괴상하네
-Very peculiar, don't you think? -Yeah.
- 그렇지 않나? - 네
Looks like the winds are changing.
바람 방향이 변했어요
Change is good.
변하는 건 좋지
Yeah, but it's not easy.
쉽진 않죠
I know what I have to do, but going back means I'll have to face my past.
내가 할 일은 알았지만 그럼 과거를 떠올려야 하는데
I've been running from it for so long.
너무 오랫동안 도망쳐 왔어요
Jeez! What was that for?
왜 때려요?
It doesn't matter. It's in the past.
과거는 상관없어
Yeah, but it still hurts.
그래도 마음이 아파요
Yes, the past can hurt.
아프긴 하겠지
But the way I see it you can either run from it
하지만 둘 중 하나야 도망치든가
or learn from it.
극복하든가
You see? So what are you going to do?
이제 어떡할 참이지?
First, I'm gonna take your stick.
일단... 지팡이부터 뱃을 거예요
No, no, no, no! Not the stick!
지팡인 안 돼!
-Hey! Where are you going? -I'm going back!
- 어딜 가는 거야? - 돌아가요!
Good! Go on! Get out of here!
그래, 어서 가라!
Grubs! Grubs!
벌레다! 벌레!
Hey. Hey, wake up.
일어나
It's okay! Whoa, whoa! It's okay! It's me!
괜찮아 나야, 나
Don't ever do that again.
다신 그러지 말아요!
Carnivores!
간 떨어질 뻔했네
-Have you guys seen Simba? -l thought he was with you.
- 심바 어덧는지 알아? - 당신과 있는 줄 알았는데
He was, but now ! can't find him. Where is he?
다투고 헤어졌는데 안 보여 어디 있는지 알아?
You won't find him here!
여기선 아무리 찾아도 없을걸
The king has returned.
왕은 돌아갔어
I can't believe it. He's gone back!
그럴 수가.… 돌아갔대!
Gone back? What do you mean?
돌아가? 무슨 뜻이야?
Hey, what's goin’ on here?
무슨 일이냐니까?
-Who's the monkey? -Simba went back to challenge Scar.
- 저 원숭인 누구야? - 심바는 스카에게 도전하러 간 거야
-Who? -Scar.
- 누구? - 스카!
-Who's got a scar? -No, it's his uncle.
- 누가 다쳤어? - 아니, 삼촌 이름이야?
-The monkey's his uncle? -No!
- 원숭이가 삼촌이야? - 아니!
Simba's gone back to challenge his uncle to take his place as king.
심바가 왕위를 되찾으러 갔단 말이야
Simba, wait up!
심바, 기다려!
-It's awful, isn't it? -I didn't want to believe you.
- 곰찍하지? - 믿고 싶지 않았어
What made you come back?
왜 마음을 바겠어?
I finally got some sense knocked into me,
제정신이 들었달까.
and I've got the bump to prove it.
더 이상은 피할 수가 없었어
Besides, this is my kingdom.
내 왕국을 위해
If l don't fight for it, who will?
내가 싸우지 않으면 누가 싸우겠어?
-I will. -It's gonna be dangerous.
- 나도 도울게 - 위험할 거야
Danger? I laugh in the face of danger.
위험? 얼마든지 오라고 해!
Il see nothing funny about this.
뭐가 우습다고 저럴까?
Timon! Pumbaa! What are you doing here?
티몬, 품바! 여긴 웹일이야?
At your service, my liege.
폐하를 도우러 왔습니다
We're gonna fight your uncle for this?
이런 땅을 위해 삼촌과 싸울 거야?
Yes, Timon. This is my home.
그래, 티몬 내 고향이니까
Talk about your fixer-upper!
재개발 좀 해야겠군
Well, Simba, if it's important to you, we're with you to the end.
그렇게 중요하다면 우리도 끝까지 돕겠습니다
Hyenas. I hate hyenas.
하이에나는 싫더라
So what's your plan for getting past those guys?
져놈들을 어떻게 따돌리지?
-Live bait. -Good idea. Hey!
- 산 미끼를 던져서 - 좋은 생각이야
Come on, Timon. You guys have to create a diversion.
어서, 티몬! 놈들의 정신을 빼놓도록 해
What do you want me to do, dress in drag and do the hula?
뭘 하란 말이야? 훌라춤이라도 출까?
Luau!
파티!
If you're hungry for a hunk of fat and juicy meat
배가 고파서 고기 생각나시면
Eat my buddy Pumbaa here because he is a treat
아주 포동통한 품바를 드세요
Come on down and dine on this tasty swine
둘이 먹다가 하나 죽어도
All you have to do is get in line
모르게 맛있대요
-Are you achin' -Yep, yep, yep.
- 뭘 드릴까? - 냐냐냐 ㅁㅁㅁ
-For some bacon?
- 싱싱한 베이컨 - 냐냐냐 ㅁㅁㅁ
-He's a big pig -Yep, yep.
- 품바 먹으면 - 냐냐 ㅁㅁ
You could be a big pig, too!
배가 엄청 나온대요
Nala, you find my mother and rally the lionesses.
날라, 어머니를 찾아가 암사자를 모아쥐
I'll look for Scar.
난 스카를 찾아갈게
Sarabi!
사라비!
Yes, Scar?
왜요, 스카?
Where is your hunting party? They're not doing their job.
사냥팀은 어덧어? 왜 할 일을 안 하는 거지?
Scar, there is no food. The herds have moved on.
사냥감이 없어요 짐승들이 다 떠났어요
No, you're just not looking hard enough.
열심히 찾지 않아서 그래!
It's over. There is nothing left.
끝났어요 아무것도 남지 않았어요
We have only one choice. We must leave Pride Rock.
여길 떠나는 수밖에요
-We're not going anywhere. -You have sentenced us to death.
- 우린 떠나지 않아 - 그건 죽으란 말이에요
-Then so be it. -You can't do that.
- 죽으라지 - 그럴 순 없어요
lam the king. l can do whatever I want.
난 왕이야 뭐든지 할 수 있어
If you were half the king Mufasa was...
무파사의 반만 됐어도 이 지경까진..…
I'm ten times the king Mufasa was!
난 무파사보다 10배는 훌륭한 왕이야!
Mufasa? No, you're dead.
무파사? 그럴 리가, 이미 죽었어
No. It's me.
아뇨, 저예요
Simba! You're alive? How can that be?
심바.… 살아 있었구나 아니, 어떻게?
It doesn't matter. I'm home.
상관없어요 제가 돌아왔어요
Simba?
심바?
Simba! I'm a little surprised to see you
심바! 살아 있었다니
alive.
정말 놀랍구나
Give me one good reason why I shouldn't rip you apart.
당신이 살아 있어야 할 이유를 하나만 대봐
Simba, you must understand.
심바, 이해해 다오
The pressures of ruling a kingdom...
나라를 통치한다는 건...
Are no longer yours. Step down, Scar.
이젠 신경 안 써도 돼 내려가, 스카
Well, I would, naturally.
물론 그래야겠지만
However, there is one little problem.
한 가지 문제가 있어
You see them?
저들이 보여?
They think I'm king.
저들은 내가 왕인 줄 알아
Well, we don't. Simba's the rightful king.
우린 아니야 진정한 왕은 심바야
The choice is yours, Scar.
선택해라, 스카
Either step down or fight.
물러나든가 싸우든가
Must this all end in violence?
무력밖엔 해결 방법이 없나?
I'd hate to be responsible for the death of a family member.
난 가족은 죽이고 싶지 않아
-Wouldn't you agree, Simba? -That's not gonna work, Scar.
- 안 그래, 심바? - 통하지 않는다, 스카
I've put it behind me.
난 전부 극복했다
But what about your faithful subjects?
숨겨진 과거는?
Have they put it behind them?
그것도 극복했나?
Simba, what is he talking about?
심바, 무슨 얘기야?
So you haven't told them your little secret.
아직 얘기하지 않은 모양이지?
Well, Simba, now's your chance to tell them.
무파사의 죽음이
Tell them who is responsible for Mufasa's death.
누구 때문이었는지 말해
lam.
나 때문이었어
It's not true.
그럴 리가!
Tell me it's not true.
사실이 아니라고 말해라
-It's true. -You see? He admits it!
- 사실이에요 - 죄를 인정했다!
-Murderer! -No! It was an accident.
- 살인자! - 그건 사고였어!
If it weren't for you, Mufasa would be alive. It's your fault he's dead!
너 때문에 네 아빠가 죽었다!
-Do you deny it? -No.
- 부인하나? - 아니
-Then you're guilty. -No, I'm not a murderer!
- 그럼 년 유죄다! - 난 살인자는 아니야!
Simba, you're in trouble again,
심바, 또 사고를 쳤군
but this time daddy isn't here to save you,
이젠 널 구해줄 아빠도 계시지 않아
and now everyone knows why!
그 이유는 모두 알고 있어
Simba!
심바!
Now, this looks familiar.
아주 낮익은 장면인데
Where have I seen this before? Let me think.
어디서 봤더라?
Yes. l remember.
그래, 이제 기억났다
This is just the way your father looked before he died.
네 아버지가 죽기 전 표정과 똑같구나
And here's my little secret.
비밀 하나 말해주지
I killed Mufasa.
무파사는 내가 죽였어
No! Murderer!
살인자!
-No, Simba, please. -Tell them the truth.
- 아니야, 심바, 제발 - 사실대로 말해
Truth? But truth is in the eye of the behold...
사실? 새삼스럽게 무슨.
All right.
좋아
I did it.
내가 했어
So they can hear you.
모두 듣게 말해
I killed Mufasa!
내가 무파사를 죽였다!
Excuse me. Pardon me. Comin’ through. Hot stuff.
좀 지나가겠습니다
-Let me out! Let me out! -Let me in! Let me in!
- 나 좀 풀어줘! - 들여 보내줘!
Please, don't eat me.
제발 날 먹지 말아요
Drop 'em!
내려뇌!
-Hey, who's the pig? -Are you talkin’ to me?
- 원 돼지야? - 나한테 한 소리야?
-He called him a pig. -To me?
- 이런, 돼지라고 불렀어 - 내게 한 소리냐고!
-Shouldn't have done that.
- 큰 실수 한 거야 - 내게 한 소리야?
-Now they're in for it. -They call me Mr. Pig!
- 너희 큰일났다 - 돼지 씨라고 불러야지!
Take that, you stupid...
그래, 잘한다!
Take that and that!
쓴맛 좀 보여줘!
Run, you yellow-belly!
그래, 도망쳐라! 이 겁쟁아!
-Murderer. -Simba. Simba, please.
- 살인자! - 심바, 제발
-Please, have mercy. I beg you. -You don't deserve to live.
- 제발 살려다오 - 년 죽어 마땅해
But Simba, l am family.
난 삼촌이잖니
It's the hyenas who are the real enemy.
진짜 적은 하이에나야
It was their fault. It was their idea.
져놈들이 시킨 짓이었어
Why should I believe you?
어떻게 믿지?
Everything you ever told me was a lie.
이제까지 거짓말만 했는데
What are you going to do?
어떡하려고?
You wouldn't kill your own uncle.
설마 삼촌을 죽이진 않겠지?
No, Scar.
아니, 스카
I'm not like you.
난 너 같지 않아
Simba, thank you. You are truly noble.
정말 고마워
I'll make it up to you, I promise. And how can I prove myself to you?
이 은혜 잊지 않을게 뭐든 말해
Tell me. l mean, anything.
시키는 대로 할게
Run.
떠나
Run away, Scar,
도망쳐, 스카
and never return.
다신 돌아오지 마
Yes.
알았어
Of course.
당연히
As you wish,
분부대로 하지요
your Majesty!
폐하!
My friends!
나의 친구들.
Friends? I thought he said we were the enemy.
친구? 아깐 적이라고 하더니만
Yeah. That's what I heard.
그래, 나도 들었어
Ed?
에드?
No. Let me explain. No, you don't understand!
내 말을 들어봐 그건 오해야
No, I didn't mean... No! No!
그런 뜻이 아니었어
It is time.
때가 되었소
Remember.
기억해라
Till we find our place
언젠간 우리
On the path unwinding
낙원을 찾겠지
In the circle
희망 안고
The circle of life
우리는 간다